AREAS OF EXPERTISE

Programming Languages and Frameworks: JavaScript (ES6), Typescript, HTML, CSS/Sass, GraphQL, Python, jQuery, Java, Laravel, PHP, NextJS, Ajax, VueJS, ReactJs, NodeJS,Express, EtherJS, Solidity, Smart-Contract, Blockchain, Dao, Web3.0, Redux, Apollo, GraphQL, Gatsby and Python.

Database and ORM: MySQL, Oracle, PostgreDB, MongoDB, Apache Casandra, Mongoose, Monk, Firebase

Tools and Platform: Git, Gulp, Web pack, Netlify, Agile, Scum, Jira, Heroku, Prismic, Contentful, Wordpress, Docker.

Testing Cypress, Selenium and Jest.

Design: AdobeXD and Figma.

PROFESSIONAL

Andela Certified web developer Google Support Professional

PERSONAL SKILLS

Able to concentrate for long periods

Problem Solving

Attention to detail

Communication skills

PERSONAL DETAILS

Segun Badmus 47053, Duisburg Deutschland

T: 01781105699

E: <u>badmu.segun@ymail.com</u>

Deutsch: A2

Segun Badmus

Fullstack Software Engineer

Portfolio: https://segunbadmus.com

PERSONAL SUMMARY

I have 5 years of professional experience that I have gained as a software engineer. I am perceived as an energetic and committed person who also write technical articles at Hashcode and Dev.to, and that can code conveniently with the modern day programming language. I am looking for a job as a software engineer in which I will use my skills and experience to implement the company guideline.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Qova Limited

FULLSTACK DEVELOPER

July 2018 - Oct 2021

- Conception, design, implementation, testing of software products.
- Analyzing user needs and developing appropriate software solution
- Write modern and robust code for a diverse array of clients and internal projects.
- Work with various languages, frameworks, and Content management system such as Javascript, PHP, NodeJS, ReactJS and Python.

Appshub Global Resource Limited

ENGINEER

Jan 2018 - July 2018

- Worked with team of designer and developer to build an E-commerce B2B platform.
- Supervise team of an E-commerce agent to carry out their responsibility.
- Interfaced with clients on a daily basis, providing technological expertise.

Duties:

- Experience in Javascript, PHP and Python.
- Knowledge of GIT, software configuration management and automated test.
- Advance knowledge of JSON, XML and UML tools.
- Knowledge of JOUERY.
- Solid understanding of E-commerce development as acquired from Appshub.
- Solid knowledge of backend development.
- Good knowledge of RESTful APIs.

KEY SKILLS AND COMPETENCIES

- Well-presented and articulate.
- Experience in solving of problems.
- Keeping up to date with the latest technology.
- Excellent listening, communication and interpersonal skills.
- Ability to divide problems to smaller chunks.

ACADEMIC QUALIFICATIONS

BSc (Hons) Computer Science Lagos State University 2011 - 2015

MSc (Hons) Computer Simulation in Science

Bergische Universitat Wuppertal 2020